A Guide to the Papers of Woodrow Wilson 1890-1907
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Woodrow Wilson, 1890-1907
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6989-a
This collection consists of 10 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the Library on June 16, 1966.
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of letters from Woodrow Wilson to various correspondents. Wilson submits an article for perusal and suggestions, comments on a circular for The State, discusses a series of articles on George Washington including illustrations by Howard Pyle, recommends some readings on The Lobby, and sends letters to be filed before an Executive Committee meeting.
Correspondents include Horace Scudder, D. C. Heath, John D. Adams, H. M. Alden, H. von Jagemann, David Friend, and Henry Pritchett.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- Woodrow Wilson to D[aniel] Collamore Heath 1890 Nov 4, ALS, 2 p.
  Comments on circular for The State; requests a copy; inquires about the sale of his book.
- Woodrow Wilson to D. C. Heath 1890 Nov 12, ALS, 1 p.
  Clarifies previous comments concerning The State; suggests using notice from Deutsche Litteraturzeitung.
- Woodrow Wilson to John D. Adams 1895 Aug 14, TLS, 4 p.
  Lists possible illustrations for the first article in a series about George Washington, a map of tidewater Virginia, a view of the Potomac River, a portrait of Colonel William Byrd, and a portrait of Alexander Spotswood are included. Asks for suggests. Mentions: Howard Pyle, Century Magazine, Putnam's Magazine, Harper's Magazine and Winsor's Narrative and Critical History of America.
- Woodrow Wilson to Henry Mills Alden 1895 Aug 26, TLS, 2 p.
  Reaches an understanding with Howard Pyle concerning the illustrations; Pyle will send Alden a copy of the manuscript; thanks him for Byrd book.
- Woodrow Wilson to Henry Mills Alden 1895 Sep 8, TLS, 2 p.
  Thanks him for copy of The Barons of the Potomac and Rappahannock; inquires about his manuscript and reports on his progress with the second article. Mentios John Kendrick Bangs, Howard Pyle and The William and Mary Quarterly.
- Woodrow Wilson to Henry Mills Alden 1895 Nov 6, TLS, 1 p.
  Thanks him for 600.00 check covering the first two articles on Washington in Harper's Magazine.
- Woodrow Wilson to Henry Mills Alden 1895 Dec 31, TLS, 1 p.
  Sends, via Adam's Express, his third article in Washington series entitled, At Home in Virginia. Mentions Howard Pyle.
- Woodrow Wilson to H. [C. G.] von Jagemann 1897 Jan 25, ALS, 2 p.
  Appreciates letter praising his work; comments on an author's need for friendly judgment; sends regards.
- Woodrow Wilson to David Friend 1901 Feb 2, TLS, 1 p.
  Never written on the "Lobby" but suggests Putnam's series, Questions of the Day; also recommends Viscount Bryce's American Commonwealth.
- Woodrow Wilson to Henry Pritchett 1907 May 21, TLS, 1 p.
  Sends letter to be filed before Executive Committee meeting; praises and recommends Dr. Price, "one of the noblest men among all the Southern teachers."